Guide to the Edward Scott-Snell papers M3007
Special Collections and University Archives, Colgate University Libraries
- Letters to Edward Scott-Snell, 1929-1946
  - ALS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 438)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 1 page (Box 6, Folder 439)
  - ALS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 440)
  - ALS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 4 pages (Box 6, Folder 441)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1932 October 11; 4 pages (Box 6, Folder 442)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 1 page (Box 6, Folder 443)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1932 December 4; 4 pages (Box 6, Folder 444)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 445)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 446)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 447)
  - APS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1933 April 1; 1 page (Box 6, Folder 448)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 6 pages (Box 6, Folder 449)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 450)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1934 November 4; 1 page (Box 6, Folder 451)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1934 November 10; 1 page (Box 6, Folder 452)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1934 November 19; 1 page (Box 6, Folder 453)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1935 January 10; 4 pages (Box 6, Folder 454)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1935 February 12; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 455)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1935 March 12; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 456)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1935 March 18; 1 page (Box 6, Folder 457)
  - ALS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1935 July 9; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 458)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 1 page (Box 6, Folder 459)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1935; 1 page (Box 6, Folder 460)
  - ALS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1935 September 16; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 461)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 3 pages (Box 6, Folder 462)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 3 pages (Box 6, Folder 463)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 464)
  - TLS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, 1937 January 23; 1 page (Box 6, Folder 465)
  - ALS from Roger Venables to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 1 page (Box 6, Folder 466)
  - ALS from Allen Walton to Edward Scott-Snell, 1931 December 7; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 467)
  - ALS from Lucy Waterhouse to Edward Scott-Snell, no year October 26; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 468)
  - ALS from Lucy Waterhouse to Edward Scott-Snell, no year August 11; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 469)
  - ALS from Lucy Waterhouse to Edward Scott-Snell, no year January 10; 1 page (Box 6, Folder 470)
  - ALS from Lucy Waterhouse to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 471)
  - ALS from Lucy Waterhouse to Edward Scott-Snell, 1932 November 2; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 472)
  - ALS from M. Charles F. Wiegner to Edward Scott-Snell, no year October 13; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 473)
  - ALS from Katherine Wiese to Edward Scott-Snell, 1934 June 6; 2 pages (Box 6, Folder 474)
  - ALS from Armine Wright to Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 1 page (Box 6, Folder 475)
- Letters to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1931-1949
  Letters to Edward's mother, especially those from her father Arthur Fell, fill out the picture of the family, as described above.
  - ALS from unknown to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1932 April 27; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 476)
  - ALS from Diana to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1934 June 15; 4 pages (Box 7, Folder 477)
  - ALS from Edla to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1932 October 6; 4 pages (Box 7, Folder 478)
  - ALS from Bobo Conin to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1932 May 2; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 479)
  - TLS from Harold S.L. Easthope to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1949; 3 pages (Box 7, Folder 480)
  - ALS from Arthur Fell to Margaret Scott-Snell, undated; 3 pages (Box 7, Folder 481)
  - ALS from Arthur Fell to Margaret Scott-Snell, undated; 4 pages (Box 7, Folder 482)
  - ALS from Arthur Fell to Margaret Scott-Snell, undated; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 483)
  - ALS from Arthur Fell to Margaret Scott-Snell, undated; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 484)
  - ALS from Arthur Fell to Margaret Scott-Snell, no year September 5; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 485)
  - ALS from Arthur Fell to Margaret Scott-Snell, no year September 3; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 486)
  - ALS from Arthur Fell to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1932 September 27; 3 pages (Box 7, Folder 487)
  - ALS from Arthur Fell to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1933 January 20; 3 pages (Box 7, Folder 488)
  - ALS from Arthur Fell to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1932 September 20; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 489)
  - ALS from Arthur Fell to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1931 November 4; 3 pages (Box 7, Folder 490)
  - ALS from Arthur Fell to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1931 February 21; 4 pages (Box 7, Folder 491)
  - ALS from Norman Long to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1935 December 21; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 492)
  - ALS from George R. Lead to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1931 November 21; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 493)
  - ALS from Katharine Little to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1931 November 20; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 494)
  - ALS from Margaret Mackail to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1943 March 8; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 495)
  - ALS from Maggie Morison to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1933 May 30; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 496)
  - ALS from May Morris to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1934 July 8; 1 page (Box 7, Folder 497)
  - ALS from May Morris to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1935 June 8; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 498)
  - ALS from May Morris to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1938; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 499)
  - ALS from May Morris to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1938 May 24; 1 page (Box 7, Folder 500)
  - ALS from May Morris to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1938 July 10; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 501)
  - ALS from A. Eleanor Neave to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1933 December 6; 4 pages (Box 7, Folder 502)
  - ALS from Mary Sloane to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1943 June 29; 3 pages (Box 7, Folder 503)
  - ALS from Stella Sydenham-Clarke to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1936 December 25; 4 pages (Box 7, Folder 504)
  - ALU from Charles Yates Fell to Arthur Fell, 1932 July 31; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 505)
- Letters and other writings by Edward Scott-Snell, 1932-1979
  This small section includes undergraduate notes and essays, poems, letters to family and friends, and most notably a sequence of eight letters to Roger Venables from 1977-1978, in which Edward reflects on the course of his life.
  - Edward Scott-Snell student essays, notes, undated; 9 pages (Box 7, Folder 506)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Sonnet XLI, "Ode to a Demon" autograph, undated; 1 page (Box 7, Folder 507)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, "Seen of a singing morning from the stone bridge" autograph, undated; 1 page (Box 7, Folder 508)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, A Villanelle, autograph, undated; 1 page (Box 7, Folder 509)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Visiting card with aurograph jottings and ink & wash sketch, undated (Box 7, Folder 510)
  - ALS from Edward Scott-Snell to Stephani Allfree, undated; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 511)
  - ALU from Edward Scott-Snell to Archibald Colquhoun, undated; 1 page (Box 7, Folder 512)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1950 March; 5 pages (Box 7, Folder 513)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1953 March; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 514)
  - ALS from Edward Scott-Snell to John Fell, undated; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 515)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1950 March; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 516)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1951 March 26; 5 pages (Box 7, Folder 517)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1951 February; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 518)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1952; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 519)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1952 March 14; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 520)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1953 March; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 521)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, Marney Cordingly, and Muriel Hodge, 1954 March; 4 pages (Box 7, Folder 522)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1955; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 523)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1957; 4 pages (Box 7, Folder 524)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1957 December 14; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 525)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1958; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 526)
  - Copy: Edward Scott-Snell to Sylvia Knowles, 1943; 1 page (Box 7, Folder 527)
  - Copy: Edward Scott-Snell to Sylvia Knowles, 1943; 1 page (Box 7, Folder 528)
  - Copy: Edward Scott-Snell to Sylvia Knowles, 1944; 1 page (Box 7, Folder 529)
  - Copy: Edward Scott-Snell to Sylvia Knowles, 1945; 3 pages (Box 7, Folder 530)
  - Copy: Edward Scott-Snell to Sylvia Knowles, 1945; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 531)
  - Copy: Edward Scott-Snell to Sylvia Knowles, 1945; 1 page (Box 7, Folder 532)
  - Copy: Edward Scott-Snell/Godwin to Margaret Scott-Snell, 1947; 1 page (Box 7, Folder 533)
  - Copy: Edward Godwin to Sylvia Knowles, 1947 September; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 534)
  - Copy: Edward Godwin to Sylvia Knowles, 1947 December 30; 3 pages (Box 7, Folder 535)
  - Copy: Edward Godwin to Sylvia Knowles, 1948 June; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 536)
  - ALS from Edward Scott-Snell to Meureg-Davies, undated; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 537)
  - Draft Letter from Edward Scott-Snell to Grant Richards, undated; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 538)
  - Three letters from Edward Scott-Snell to Roger, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 539)
  - APS from Edward Scott-Snell: toast to Edith Sitwell, undated; 1 page (Box 7, Folder 540)
  - ALS from Edward Scott-Snell to Roger Venables, 1932 December 31; 4 pages (Box 7, Folder 541)
  - ACU from Edward Scott-Snell to Roger Venables, undated; 1 page (Box 7, Folder 542)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Roger Venables, 1977 December; 4 pages (Box 7, Folder 543)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Roger Venables, 1978 February; 6 pages (Box 7, Folder 544)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Roger Venables, 1978 February; 7 pages (Box 7, Folder 545)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Roger Venables, 1978 March 11; 7 pages (Box 7, Folder 546)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Roger Venables, 1978 April; 8 pages (Box 7, Folder 547)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Roger Venables, 1978 May; 8 pages (Box 7, Folder 548)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Roger Venables, 1978 July; 7 pages (Box 7, Folder 549)
  - ALS from Edward Godwin to Roger Venables, 1978 August 20; 7 pages (Box 7, Folder 550)
  - ALS from Edward Scott-Snell to Mr. Wallace, 1933 September 30; 2 pages (Box 7, Folder 551)
- Letters from Stephani Godwin, 1948-1955
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1948 May 6; 6 pages (Box 8, Folder 552)
  - TLU and ALS from Stephani Godwin, Lists of property, 1948; 7 pages (Box 8, Folder 553)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1948 December 22; 3 pages (Box 8, Folder 554)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1949 March 26; 2 pages (Box 8, Folder 555)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1949 June 31; 4 pages (Box 8, Folder 556)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1949 July 11; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 557)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1949 July 20; 4 pages (Box 8, Folder 558)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1949 August 30; 4 pages (Box 8, Folder 559)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1949 October 1; 3 pages (Box 8, Folder 560)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Muriel Hodge and Marney Cordingley, 1949 November 19; 6 pages (Box 8, Folder 561)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1949 November 25; 5 pages (Box 8, Folder 562)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1950 March 4; 4 pages (Box 8, Folder 563)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1950 February; 6 pages (Box 8, Folder 564)
  - ALU from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1950 April 24; 4 pages (Box 8, Folder 565)
  - TLS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1950 June 5; 3 pages (Box 8, Folder 566)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1950 August 3; 2 pages (Box 8, Folder 567)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1950 December 18; 2 pages (Box 8, Folder 568)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1951 January 6; 5 pages (Box 8, Folder 569)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, Muriel Hodge, and Joscelyn Godwin, 1951 March 6; 6 pages (Box 8, Folder 570)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1951 July 12; 4 pages (Box 8, Folder 571)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1951 July 18; 2 pages (Box 8, Folder 572)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1951 September 25; 4 pages (Box 8, Folder 573)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1951 October 21; 3 pages (Box 8, Folder 574)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1952 January 14; 2 pages (Box 8, Folder 575)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1952 January 14; 5 pages (Box 8, Folder 576)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1952 April 22; 4 pages (Box 8, Folder 577)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1952 June 4; 5 pages (Box 8, Folder 578)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1952 October 10; 2 pages (Box 8, Folder 579)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Muriel Hodge, 1952 November 1; 3 pages (Box 8, Folder 580)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1953 March 28; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 581)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1953 October 30; 3 pages (Box 8, Folder 582)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1953 December 7; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 583)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1953 December 17; 3 pages (Box 8, Folder 584)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1954 January 8; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 585)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1954 February 11; 3 pages (Box 8, Folder 586)
  - ALS from Stephani Godwin to Marney Cordingley, 1955 December 8; 4 pages (Box 8, Folder 587)
- Letters from Felix Godwin, 1949-1953
  - ALS from Felix Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1949 August 30; 3 pages (Box 8, Folder 588)
  - ALS from Felix Godwin to Marney Cordingly, 1949 September; 3 pages (Box 8, Folder 589)
  - ALS from Felix Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1950 June 31; 4 pages (Box 8, Folder 590)
  - ALS from Felix Godwin to Joscelyn Godwin, 1953 July 8; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 591)
- Early educational and professional activities, 1930-1937
  This series includes several items from Edward Scott-Snell's early educational and professional life.
  First, several items document Edward's undergraduate life, including Edward's bank book (1930-1935), which records all his income and expenditures, bills, police sumons, Edward's futile search for employment after his graduation from Oxford, and his enrollment in the Slade School of Art of the University of London, 1933-1934.
  Materials related to Edward's first one-man exhibition at Ryman's Oxford, 1936, are also present and include an illustrated catalogue and the list of forty-nine pictures sold with prices. Present ownership and location of these items are noted when known.
  Another grouping of materials documents the rise and fall of Houghton & Scott-Snell, Ltd., a publishing company formed with the help of capital from Edward's mother, Margaret Scott-Snell (and perhaps from Sir Arthur Fell). The company survived from 1933-1937 and published about a dozen titles. Some had jacket illustrations by Edward, and two were illustrated by him throughout: John F. Macpherson's Peter, Pam, and the Wizard and Evangeline Deverell's Alan Singh, or The Land of Magic.
  Edward worked from 1937-1948 as a teacher in publice (i.e. private) schools. Included in this series are testimonials from school and college principals, documenting his attendance at King's School, Wimbledon, and at art schools (Ruskin School of Art, Slade School of Art, Byam Shaw School of Art), and his teaching (Radley, Rugby, Christ's Hospital, Merchant Taylors). A letter acknowledging Edward's donation to the Radley College Archives of a water-color design for a rose-garden is also found in this series.
  - Richard Hennings, "Sir Walter Scott", 1932; 1 item (Box 8, Folder 592)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Barclays Bank Book, 1930-1935; 1 item (Box 8, Folder 593)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Social Events. Party invitation, 1931 June 13; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 594)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Social events. Meadows society dinner, 1931 November 23 (Box 8, Folder 595)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Social events. George III party, no year February 27 (Box 8, Folder 596)
  - English Club: Letter from The Tatler, 1932 October 24; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 597)
  - English Club Program, 1932 October 25; 2 copies (Box 8, Folder 598)
  - English Club poster for Dunsany, 1932 November 14; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 599)
  - English Club dinner bill, 1932 November 17; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 600)
  - English Club program, 1932 November 29 (Box 8, Folder 601)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Christ Church bill, 1932 December 25; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 602)
  - English Club Program, 1933 January 27 (Box 8, Folder 603)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Slade School of Arts, registration, 1933-1934; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 604)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Oxford Art Agency, 1933 October 5; 2 pages (Box 8, Folder 605)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Oxford Art Agency terms, 1933 October 9; 2 pages (Box 8, Folder 606)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Museum cast order, 1933 October 18-20; 2 pages (Box 8, Folder 607)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Police Summons and receipt, 1935 February 19 and 1934 January 17 (Box 8, Folder 608)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, bill from Liberty's for gift to his sister, 1933 November 21; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 609)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, bill from Blackwell's, 1933 December 15; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 610)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, bill from Shakespeare Head Press, 1933 December; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 611)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Special Egg Cup, 1933 October 19; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 612)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Bill from Austin Reed, 1934 January 19; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 613)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, bill from Bolt & Co., 1934 September 20; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 614)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Bill from Craig & Davies, 1936 November 5; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 615)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Triumph Car refrain, 1935 June 4; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 616)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Bill from Fribourg & Freyer, 1935 January 20; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 617)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, bill from Fribourg & Freyer with his autograph apology, 1937 July 5; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 618)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Junior Constitutional Clubb election, 1934 August 23; 2 pages (Box 8, Folder 619)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, Junior Constitutional Club apology, 1935 October 20; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 620)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, job-hunting, draft of application, 1934 November 5; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 621)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, job-hunting, draft letter of application, 1935 January 26; 1 page (Box 8, Folder 622)
  - Edward Scott-Snell, job hunting replies - negative, 1934-1935; 13 pages (Box 8, Folder 623)
- Early Creative Work, undated
  This series comprises drawings and sketches by Edward Scott-Snell, 1925-1937. There are 130 items in this collection, ranging from small sketches and paintings in wash to fully finished drawings. Together they demonstrate Edward's growth as an artist from his teenage years through his many contributions to Oxford's Isis and Cherwell magazines, and after that as a book illustrator for his own publishing company, Houghton & Scott-Snell, Ltd.
  - See list of possible drawings inside box, undated; 3 photographs (Box 9)
- At Kelmscott Manor, 1885-1988
  Biographical note
  Edward's mother, Margaret Scott-Snell, made friends with May Morris, daughter of William Morris, who lived in Kelmscott Manor with her companion Miss Lobb. On May Morris's death, the manor was left to Oxford University for the use of artists. Edward Scott-Snell and his mother were the first tenants, and the manor was Edward's home exclusively from 1943-1948. In 1940 he married Stephani Allfree (born 1917), the daughter of Lt. Geoffrey S. Allfree, R[oyal] B[ritish] A[rtist] (1889-1918). She was later known as a painter and poet under the name of "Godwin." Edward and Stephani's sons Felix (1941) and Joscelyn (1945) were born during this period.
  This series contains photographs, letters, and papers relating to Kelmscott, and specimens of Edward and Stephani's literary and artistic work from their time there, notably their jointly-written and illustrated life of William Morris,Warrior Bard(1947). This work was their first publication after they changed their surname from Scott-Snell to Godwin. Also found in this seires is Thessyros, a book of poems written and illustrated by Stephani, which contain keys to the mysterious imagery of her and Edward's paintings of the Kelmscott period.
  Also found in this series are a prospectus for a boarding school for young boys, which Edward and Stephani ran at the manor and a catalogue of Edward and Stephani Godwin's exhibition at Ryman's, Oxford (October 1944), which presented the fruit of their wartime years at Kelmscott. Fifty-three pictures were sold at this exhibition, while most of the rest were lost, after having been deposited in the 1950s with a Fr. Martin Leahy in Brooklyn.
  Copies of Martin Knowles's geneological studies and family trees are also included in this series. These studies explain the relationships of the Scott-Snells, Fells, and others, and provide researchers with valuable infomation about these families. A booklet by Edward's aunt Winifred Whitehead, entitled Wimbledon 1885-1965, contains photographs of Sir Arthur Fell and his family at Lauriston House (since destroyed). The gardens of Lauriston House and the life that was lived there were a permanent element in Edward's imagination.
  - Postcard photograph of May Morris in the garden of Kelmscott, undated; 1 page (Box 10, Folder 624)
  - 5 photographs of Kelmscott Manor, 1930s; 5 photographs (Box 10, Folder 625)
  - 2 photographs of Margaret Scott-Snell at Kelmscott Manor, 1930s; 2 photographs (Box 10, Folder 626)
  - Kelmscott Manor school prospectives, with drawing by Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 2 pages (Box 10, Folder 627)
  - 2 modern picture postcards of Kelmscott Manor, undated; 2 items (Box 10, Folder 628)
  - Photograph (book proof?) of May Morris, undated; 1 photograph (Box 10, Folder 629)
  - Stephani & Edward Scott-Snell, Prospectives for Christmas cards, undated; 1 page (Box 10, Folder 630)
  - 2 photographs of Edward Scott-Snell, undated; 2 photographs (Box 10, Folder 631)
  - Christmas Card, Edward Godwin, "Gloria in exelsis", undated; 1 page (Box 10, Folder 632)
  - Christmas card, Stephani Scott-Snell, "The Christ Child of Poland", undated; 1 page (Box 10, Folder 633)
  - Christmas card, Stephani & Edward Scott-Snell, "L'Amor Che Muove", undated; 1 page (Box 10, Folder 634)
  - Christmas card, Stephani Scott-Snell, "Venite Adoremus", undated; 1 page (Box 10, Folder 635)
  - Christmas card, Stephani Godwin, "Adeste Fideles", undated; 1 page (Box 10, Folder 636)
  - Christmas card, Edward Scott-Snell, "Flying Gloria", undated; 1 page (Box 10, Folder 637)
  - Picture postcard, Stephani & Edward Scott-Snell, "The Lion Angel", undated; 1 page (Box 10, Folder 638)
  - Photographs of unidentified people (Box 10, Folder 639)
  - Stephani Scott-Snell, "Thessyros" 1st state, undated; 1 item (Box 11, Folder 640)